freightquote.com 2019-04-01

# Privacy Policy | Freightquote

## Details on what we do with your information.

## Freightquote.com, Inc. Privacy Policy

### Policy Effective Date

This policy is effective as of January 23, 2019 and replaces any and all previous versions.

### Scope and Application of Policy

Freightquote.com, Inc. and its parent company for and on behalf of its subsidiaries (collectively “Freightquote”) created this policy (the “Privacy Policy”) in order to demonstrate our commitment to privacy. The policy describes collection, use, storage, sharing and protection of your personal information for the Freightquote.com website and all related sites, applications, services and tools where this policy is referenced, regardless of how you access or use them, including mobile devices.

### Consent

By using the Freightquote.com website and its related sites, products, applications, services and tools, or registering for an account with Freightquote, you expressly consent to the collection, use, disclosure and retention of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy. Further, you acknowledge, consent and agree that we may access, preserve, and disclose your registration and any other information you provide if required to do so by law or in a good faith belief that such access preservation or disclosure is reasonably necessary in our opinion to: (1) comply with legal process, including, but not limited to, civil and criminal subpoenas, court orders, other compulsory disclosures, or at the advice of legal counsel; (2) respond to claims of a violation of the rights of third parties, whether or not the third party is a user, individual, or government agency; or (3) protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Freightquote, our users or the public. 

Throughout this Privacy Policy, we use the term “personal information” to describe information that can be associated with a specific person and could be used to identify that person. We do not consider personal information to include information that has been made anonymous or aggregated so that it can no longer be used, whether in combination with other information or otherwise, to identify a specific person. 

Users may check the Privacy Policy periodically to view any changes or updates. We may amend this Privacy Policy at any time by posting the amended terms on this site. All amended terms automatically take effect 30 days after they are initially posted on this site.

### Mobile Privacy

We may offer you the ability to connect with our sites, or use our applications, services and tools using a mobile device, through a mobile optimized website or mobile application. The provisions of this policy apply to all such mobile access and use of mobile devices. 

### Collection of Personal Information

We obtain personal information in order to provide you with the use of and access to our sites, applications, services and tools, and to help us personalize and improve your experience and the services we offer. If you choose to provide us with personal information, you consent to the transfer and storage of that information on our servers located in the United States.

**Information we collect automatically** : When you visit our sites, use our applications, services and tools, or interact with our advertising or content, we automatically collect information sent to us by your computer, mobile device or other access device. This information includes, but is not limited to:

  * The Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet; standard web log information; login, email address and password; the type of device used to access our website and unique identification; computer and connection information, such as browser type, version, and time zone setting; geographic location and navigation information; the full Uniform Resource Locator (URL) clickstream to, through, and from our website; statistics to measure and collect session information; and other anonymous information through the use of cookies and web beacons.

**Information you give us** : During the registration process, Freightquote requires users to give us contact information. If you register for an account with us, you give us your personal information, and you are not anonymous to us. We collect and store any information you enter on our sites or you provide to us in context of using our sites, applications, services or tools. This may include, but is not limited to:

  * Name, physical and billing address; phone numbers; credit card information; shipment information, including shipping and receiving addresses; names and email addresses of people to whom shipments are being delivered or picked up; date and time of shipment; and shipping volumes, type of mode transport, and product descriptions.

**Information from other sources** : We may receive or collect supplemental information about you from third party sources and add it to our account information. This may include, but not limited to, demographic information, additional contact information, updated delivery information from our carriers, and additional information about you from credit bureaus or other sources, as permitted by law. We also contract with agents or trade associations, who may enroll new users by submitting account information to Freightquote such as company name, physical address and email address. Freightquote uses this information to create new accounts. 

### Information Sharing and Registration with Social Media Websites

Freightquote uses various social media sites to communicate about or advertise our business. We will not publish any personal data from our customers on these sites. We do not gain access to your email address or have any access to your personal data while you use social media sites to interact with Freightquote. Any request for personal information or shipment data to help us assist a shipper on these sites will be done through one-on-one messaging. While using social media sites, you are subject to the terms and conditions of these sites. 

### Use of Personal Information

Our primary purpose in collecting personal information is to provide you with access to our sites and/or use of our services, applications and tools, provide you with requested customer service and relevant information about your account and our services, and to provide you with a safe, smooth, efficient and customized experience. 

We may use your personal information to provide access information to our services and tools; to perform general account servicing such as address verification and confirmation of shipments tendered; to collect your shipment information in order to process your shipment and generate an electronic pickup with a freight carrier and to forward shipping documents to the shipping or receiving parties; to customize your address book to simplify and speed up the shipment booking process and to allow Freightquote to contact a stored address if a shipment tendered cannot be delivered; to deliver notification of service updates and explanation of services; to customize, measure and improve our services, content and advertising; to deliver targeted marketing and promotional offers based on your communication preferences; to perform digital advertising, to contact you, either via email or telephone, to resolve disputes, collect fees and troubleshoot problems with your account or our sites, services, applications, or tools, or for other purposes as authorized by law; to provide you with other services requested by you as described when we collect the information.

### Communication Preferences

By providing Freightquote with your contact information and registering to use our services, you agree to receive marketing communications by email, direct mail, and other marketing sources. Freightquote provides users the opportunity to unsubscribe from receiving marketing communications via email by calling 800.323.5441, by emailing contactus@Freightquote.com, or by choosing to unsubscribe at the bottom of any Freightquote marketing email.

### Marketing, Advertising and Pop-Ups

Freightquote does not sell advertising anywhere on our website. If you see advertising pop up messages while using our website, they are not being served by Freightquote and are in no way endorsed or encouraged by Freightquote. 

Freightquote uses remarketing and retargeting to advertise online. When you visit or interact with our sites, services, applications, email and other tools, we or our authorized service providers may use third party cookies (ex. Google) to show advertisements on websites across the Internet. Third party vendors, including, but not limited to, Google and social media sites, use cookies to serve ads based on someone’s past visits to [Freightquote.com](https://www.freightquote.com/). You may opt out third party vendor’s use of cookies by visiting [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1). 

For more information about how Google Analytics, Adobe Analytics, Hubspot, Facebook, and/or LinkedIn uses cookies, see the privacy resources for each identified below:

Google Analytics - https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites

Adobe Analytics - https://marketing.adobe.com/resources/help/en_US/reference/c_Privacy_Overview.html

Hubspot - https://legal.hubspot.com/privacy-policy

Facebook - https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation

LinkedIn - https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy

Some web browsers may transmit “do not track” signals to websites with which the browser communicates. Because of differences in how web browsers incorporate and activate this feature, it is not always clear whether users intend for these signals to be transmitted, or whether they even are aware of them. Freightquote does not currently take action in response to these signals. 

### Our Disclosure of Your Information

We limit the disclosure of personal information to third parties to information required for shipment administration, including, but not limited to, shipping and receiving information, which we submit electronically to the freight carrier. 

In certain situations, we may disclose your personal information to respond to legal requirements, enforce our policies, respond to claims that a listing or other content violates the rights of others, or protect anyone’s rights, property, or safety. Such information will be disclosed in accordance with this Privacy Policy and applicable laws and regulations. We may also share your personal information with: 

Trade associations, whose access is restricted to the names and addresses of their own members or Agents, whose access is restricted to the account and shipment information for those users they have enrolled. Associations and Agents have no direct access to any Freightquote databases. 

Law enforcement, governmental agencies, or authorized third-parties, in connection with or in response to a criminal investigation, investigation of fraud, intellectual property infringement, piracy, or other alleged unlawful or illegal activity or any other activity that may expose us, you, or any other Freightquote user to legal liability. In such events, we will only disclose information relevant and necessary to the investigation or inquiry, such as name, street address, city, state, ZIP code, telephone number, email address, User ID history, IP address, fraud complaints, shipping addresses, transported commodity description and listing history, and anything else we may deem relevant to the investigation. 

Credit bureaus, with which we may report information about your account, including information on late payments, missed payments, or other defaults that may be reflected in your credit report. 

Other business entities, should we plan to merge with, acquire or be acquired by that business entity. (Should such a combination occur, we will require that the new combined entity follow this Privacy Policy with respect to your personal information. If your personal information will be used contrary to this policy, you will receive prior notice.) 

We may engage other companies to perform certain functions on our behalf. Examples include sending direct and electronic mail, printing and mailing invoices, analyzing data and providing marketing analysis. Third parties performing these limited functions on our behalf shall have access to our user’s personal information as needed to perform these functions, but we do not permit them to use your personal information for other purposes.

### Information You Share on Freightquote

If you access our sites from a shared computer, certain information about you, such as your account user information or shipment activity, may also be visible to other individuals who use the computer after you. We encourage you to properly log out and close your browser window to prevent others from accessing your personal information.  

### How We Protect and Store Your Personal Information

We store and process your personal information on our computers in the United States. We protect your information using technical and administrative security measures to reduce the risks of loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure and alteration of information. Some of the safeguards we use are firewalls and data encryption to verify access to the Freightquote systems and physical access controls to our data centers. Member access is restricted by the use of an email address and password. 

We take steps to ensure that the personal information we collect is accurate and up to date, and we provide you with the opportunity to update your information through your account profile settings. We retain information as long as it is necessary and relevant for our operations. In addition, we may retain personal information from closed accounts to comply with law, prevent fraud, collect any fees owed, resolve disputes, and take other actions as permitted by law. 

### Our Use of Cookies

When you visit or interact with our sites, services, applications, messaging (such as email), and tools, we use cookies to help us recognize your browser as a previous visitor and save and remember any preferences that may have been set while your browser was visiting our website. We may also record your password in a cookie. Please note that log-ins, passwords and any other account-related information included in such cookies are encrypted for security purposes. Unless you register with us, these cookies will not contain any personal information. 

### No Spam, Spyware or Spoofing

We and our users do not tolerate spam. To report company-related spam or spoof emails to Freightquote, please forward the email to report-spam@freightquote.com. You may not use our communication tools to send spam or otherwise send content that would violate our Terms and Conditions. We automatically scan and may manually filter messages to check for spam, viruses, phishing attacks and other malicious activity or illegal or prohibited content. 

### Accessing, Reviewing, and Changing Your Personal Information

You can see, review and change most of your personal information by signing on to Freightquote.com. You must promptly update your personal information if it changes or is inaccurate. We give users the following options for changing and modifying information previously provided. 

  * Email a request to [contactus@Freightquote.com](mailto:contactus@Freightquote.com). 
  * Call us with your request at 800.323.5441. 
  * Submit any edits via the "My Account Info" link on our website. 
  * Mail written instructions to: Freightquote.com, Inc., 901 West Carondelet Drive, Kansas City, MO 64114. 

### Third Parties

Except as otherwise expressly included in this Privacy Policy, this document addresses only the use and disclosure of information we collect from you. If you disclose your information to others, whether they are carriers or other users on our sites or other sites throughout the internet, different rules may apply to their use or disclosure of the information you provide to them. Freightquote does not control the privacy policies of third parties, and you are subject to the privacy policies of those third parties where applicable. We encourage you to ask questions before you disclose your personal information to others. 

### Use of the Website by Children

Our site is not designed for, or directed to, children under the age of 18 and Freightquote does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 18. 

We are committed to complying with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 ("COPPA") and other applicable laws. If you are under 18 years of age, please do not use our website. 

### International Users of the Website

Freightquote is committed to compliance with applicable privacy laws and is committed to protecting the personal information of international users. By use of the website and Freightquote services, international users consent to the use of their personal information for the purposes as outlined in this Privacy Policy and waive any applicable laws or regulations that may otherwise be applicable to the use of personal information in the country in which the international user is located. 

### Our GDPR (General Data Protection Directive) Processing Principals

If your rights and freedoms are protected under the European Union's Regulation (EU) 2016/679, we will only process your personal data if we established a legal basis for such processing.  We will only process your information to the extent that you consented to such processing, or if processing is required in the performance of a contractual obligation, for the purposes of legal obligation in which we must comply, for the vital interests of individuals, for public interest, or for a legitimate interest.  In addition, we will only process your personal data for the purpose it was originally collected, or unless you provide explicit consent to additional processing.  We will limit our processing of your personal data to such data that is proportionate to attain its purpose, we will retain your personal data so long as to attain the specific purposes for such data, except where required to retain longer in which we will duly inform you, and we will implement technical and organizational security measures to protect your personal data from accidental loss, destruction, or damage.  

You have certain rights in accordance with the GDPR.  Specifically, your rights include:

  * The right to receive information about your relationship with Freightquote;
  * The right to obtain our confirmation regarding whether your personal data is being processed;
  * The right for us to inform you of your rights to have your personal data corrected, if inaccurate, and to be erased or "forgotten" upon completion of such processing or upon your valid request or withdrawal of consent;
  * The right to restrict our processing of your personal data if the accuracy of such data is contested, or, if Freightquote no longer needs your personal data for its original purpose;
  * The right to receive copies of all your personal data in our possession in a structured, commonly used, and machine readable format;
  * The right to transmit your personal data in our possession to another controller without hindrance from Freightquote;

To exercise your rights under the GDPR, please contact us as specified below.

### Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this website, you can contact us at: 

email: [contactus@Freightquote.com](mailto:contactus@Freightquote.com)  
phone: 800.323.5441
